所以，我们是美丽的人们，你们将要学习Linux操作系统皇冠上的明珠
So here we are you beautiful people you're about to learn the crown jewel of the Linux operating system
管道。
piping.
在上几个视频中，您已经了解到可以使用重定向来更改位置
So in the last few videos you've learned that you can use redirection to change the location of where
您可以发送命令输出以及从哪里获得命令输入。
you send command output and where you get command input.
但是，如果您想要连接一个命令的标准输出，使其流入标准
But what if you wanted to connect the standard output of one command so that it flowed into the standard
输入另一个命令。
input of another command.
这就是管道的用武之地，它的威力大得离谱。
Well that's where piping comes in and it's ridiculously powerful.
每个Linux命令都被设计成非常好地完成一项任务。
Each Linux command is designed to do one task extremely well.
因此，如果您能够不断地将这些高度专门化的命令输送到一起，并在它们之间传递数据
So if you can continually pipe these highly specialized commands together and pass data between them
你可以建造先进的管道来完成几乎任何你能想到的任务，一旦你知道
you can build advanced pipelines to do pretty much any task that you can think of and once you know
如何做到这一点，会让人感觉真的像是一个超级大国。
how to do it it will really feel like a super power.
因此，在这段视频中，您将了解如何构建您自己的命令管道。
So in this video you're going to learn how to build your very own command pipelines.
然后在第二部分的下一个视频中，您将学习如何使您的管道更加灵活
And then in the next video in part two you're going to learn how to make your pipelines more flexible
通过使用T和Exarchs命令。
by using the T and the Exarchs commands.
这将是课程的一个很棒的部分，在你学习之后，你将不会认出你自己。
This is going to be a great section of the course and you will not recognize yourself after you learn
我接下来要教你的东西。
what I'm about to teach you.
所以我希望你会很兴奋。
So I hope you're excited.
让我们继续往前走，开始做这件事吧。
Let's go ahead and get into it.
好的。
OK.
因此，管道就是获取一个命令的标准输出，并将其连接到标准输入
So piping is all about taking the standard output of one command and connecting it to the standard input
执行另一个命令。
of another command.
让我们以data命令为例，我们知道date命令会显示日期。
So let's take for example the DATA command the date command as we know will show us the date.
现在，我们可以使用以下命令将DATE命令的标准输出写入名为DATE DirectX DXi的文本文件
Now we can write the standard output of the date command to a text file called Date directx DXi using
重定向。
redirection.
所以这是一个小小的挑战。
So it a mini challenge.
看看你能不能记得怎么做。
See if you can remember how to do that.
如何使用DATA命令并将其重定向到名为DATE的文件中。
How would you take the data command and redirect it into a file called Date.
XTi博士试一试，然后回来看看你做得怎么样。
Dr. XTi give it a go and then come back to see how you did.
你成功了吗。
Did you manage it.
这是一种您可以这样做的方法，您可以键入date命令，然后说我想重定向
Well this is one way you could do it you could type the date command and then say I want to redirect
将标准输出转换为Data Darty XTi。
the standard output into data Darty XTi.
现在你可以把这个符号放在数字1的位置来表示
Now you could have just had the symbol like this where you could have put the number one to indicate
您想要将第一个数据流，即标准输出写入到DATEDET60。
that you wanted the first data stream which is standard output to be written to date dot 60.
如果你做了那么多的祝贺，你已经学到了。
And if you did that massive Congratulations you're learning already.
现在我们已经完成了这项工作，我们将在这里查看我们的文件资源管理器，我们会看到一个名为
But now that we've done it we are going to take a look at our file explorer here and we see a file called
Dottie XTi，我们看到日期信息确实已经写入到该文件中。
Dottie XTi and we see that the date information has indeed been written into that file.
好的。
OK.
但是现在，如果我们只想删掉一周中的某一天，在本例中是星期一，该怎么办呢？
But now what if we wanted to just cut out the day of the week which in this case is Monday.
好的。
OK.
我们怎么才能把一周中的某一天。
How would we cut out just the day of the week.
要做到这一点，一种方法是使用CUT命令。
Well one way to do it would be to use the cut command.
你以前没见过厨师上场，但它的操作非常简单，而且可能更容易展示
Now you haven't seen the cook come on before but it works very simply and it's probably easier to show
你通过做什么。
you by doing.
首先，我们要读取将文件放入命令的标准输入的日期。
First we want to read the date that takes the file into the standard input for the command.
因此，要做到这一点，我们需要键入Cut，然后读取标准输入日期。
So to do that we would type cut and then read into the standard input date.
多蒂·西蒂。
Dottie XTi.
好的。
OK.
你不一定要有零，所以你可以只得到零，你知道的，只要做到这一点就行了
And you don't have to have the zero so you could just get with zero and just you know just do that have
少于号，然后是日期。
the less than sign and then date takes.
记住这里的空间。
And remember the space here.
这是可选的。
This is optional.
好的，我可能会留着它，因为它看起来更好看一些。
Ok I'll probably just keep it because it looks a bit nicer.
现在，库克要做的是，它将切割一个文件，并为您提供特定的列。
Now what Cook will do what the cook does is it will cut up a file and give you specific columns.
如果我们看一下Dottie XTi，您可以想象文件被分成几列，其间有一个空格
So if we look at Dottie XTi you can imagine that the file is broken up into columns with a space between
每列。
each column.
在本例中，星期一是一周中的第几天，它是第一列或第一个字段，这在
The day of the week in this case Monday is the first column or the first field as it's known in the
指挥部。
command.
这将是第二个字段。
This would be the second field.
这将是第三个领域，以此类推。
This would be the third field and so on and so on.
但是我们希望第一场比赛能够取得成功，并且对我们来说是正确的。
But we want the first field to make the cut come on and work correctly for us.
我们认为使用期权的两条信息。
We think that two pieces of information using options.
首先，我们需要给它指定长形式的分隔符选项，所以分隔符。
First we need to give it the delimiter long form option so delimiter.
好吧。
Okay.
这就是一个分隔符，它告诉你是什么分隔了这些列。
And what that was a delimiter is is it tells you what divides the columns.
好的，我们需要告诉它空格是被分割的，或者分隔列，因为空格就是被分割的
OK so we need to tell it that space is divide or delimit the columns because spaces are what divided
在文件中向上显示这些特定的列。
up these specific columns in The File.
好的。
OK.
要做到这一点，我们只需键入分隔符as，作为空格，然后用引号将其放入空格。
So to do that we just type delimiter as along for a space and then in quotes put into the space.
好的，我们说空格是这个文件或输入的分隔符。
OK so we're saying a space is what delimits this file or this input.
好的。
OK.
然后我们需要说明我们想要哪个字段，现在我们已经告诉它文件是如何分割的，所以我们给出
Then we need to say which field we want and now that we've told it how the file is cut up so we give
这也是长格式选项，即字段，然后是空格，然后是一个。
it again the long form option which is fields and then a space and then one.
好的。
OK.
现在，当我们运行它的时候，我们得到了什么。
And now what we've got there when we run that.
好的。
OK.
我们要看到的是我们要对科赫指挥部说。
What we're going to see is we're saying to the Koch command.
好的，读取DirectX Take的日期。
OK read Date directx take.
它被分成几列，每一列都有空格隔开。
It's broken up into columns with us each with a space separating each column.
我们想要第一块地。
And we want the first field.
现在，当我按Enter键时，您可以看到我们得到的是星期一作为输出。
Now when I press enter you can see that we get Monday as an output.
是不是太棒了，对吧。
Isn't that awesome right.
那真是太酷了。
That's pretty cool.
你以前没见过来吧。
You've not seen the come on before.
这是一个很酷的命令，但是这个很管用，但是有点笨拙。
It's very cool command but this this works but it's kind of clunky.
好的，首先，我们将date命令的标准输出写入一个文件，该文件占用了
OK first we're writing the standard output of the date command to a file which takes up space on our
电脑。
computer.
现在，我们必须将该文件读入命令。
Right then we have to read that file into the command.
好的。
OK.
也许在获得正确的数据之后，我们必须删除这个原始文件，因为
And maybe we would also after getting this data right we then have to delete this original file because
我们不再需要了，这是我们必须进行的另一个过程。
we don't need anymore which is another process that we have to undertake.
因此，通过将数据保存到文件中，然后分两步读取该文件，这样做需要一个
So doing it this way by saving the data into a file and then reading that file in two steps takes a
打字要多得多。
lot more typing.
它会产生不必要的文件，您必须删除这些文件，否则它们只会占用空间。
It makes unnecessary files which you've got to remove or they just take up space.
这只是一种低效和笨拙的做事方式。
It's just inefficient and awkward way of doing things.
因此，我们可以通过管道将DATA命令的标准输出直接传输到
So instead we can pipe the standard output of the data command directly into the standard input of the
剪切命令。
cut command.
好的。
OK.
所以如果我只用箭头键来保留我们以前拥有的东西。
So if I just use the arrow key to keep what we have before.
好的。
OK.
现在不是说read into the read into标准输入命令date xti，而是我要
Now instead of saying read into the read into the standard input command date XTi what I'm going to
我要做的就是输入日期，然后使用这个管子符号。
do is I'm going to type date and then use this pipe symbol.
现在，您可以通过按住Shift键，然后在大多数键盘上使用反斜杠来找到此管道符号
Now this pipe symbol you can find by holding Shift and then backslash on your on your most keyboards
不管怎么说。
anyway.
所以，是的，大多数键盘上都是这样。
So yep that's the way it is on most keyboards.
但是如果键盘上没有，如果按住Shift和反斜杠是不可能的，那就跳起来吧
But if it's not there on your keyboard if it's not possible by holding Shift and backslash just hop
放到搜索引擎上，看看如何在键盘布局上做管道符号。
onto a search engine and look for how to do the pipe symbol on your keyboard layout.
如果你找不到它，你应该马上上来。
If you have trouble finding it you should should come up straight away.
但是现在发生的情况是，我们说通过管道将来自标准输出的日期中的数据输入到
But now what's happening is we're saying pipe the data from the date come on standard output into the
柯克曼的标准输入。
Kirkman's standard input.
现在，因为最多60个数据实际上是date命令的标准输出，所以它将
Now because data up to 60 was effectively the standard output from the date command this is going to
都有同样的效果，所以我们会按Enter键，这样我们就可以在周一出来了。
have the same effect so will we press enter that we get Monday out.
而这一切都是一步到位的。
And this happened all in one step.
这真的很酷，我们设法直接从date命令中获取数据，并将其通过管道传输到
So that's really cool we managed to take the data straight from the date command and pipe it into the
命令的标准输入，以便可以对其进行操作。
standard input of the command so that it can be operated on.
我们给厨师命令提供了一些选项，使我们可以直接切出当天的名称
We gave the cook command some options that allowed us to cut out directly the name of the day of the
星期。
week.
现在我要按下“向上都可以”，现在我要给你们看一些很酷的东西。
Now I'm just going to press the up are OK and now I'm going to show you something really cool.
我们所能做的就是将这些数据放入文件中。
What we can do is we can actually put that data into file.
好的。
OK.
所以我们实际上可以使用重定向将其保存到一个名为TODAY的文件中。
So we could actually save that using redirection into a file called today.
逃离。
Xscape.
来看看这个。
So check this out.
使用date命令在此处获取所有这些信息。
Using the date command to get all this information here.
我们把它剪掉，只得到周一，然后我们把这些数据写入一个名为今天的文件中，该文件
We're cutting it out to get just Monday and then we're writing that data into a file called today that
痒痒的，相当棒的，对吧。
tickety pretty awesome right.
所以让我们试一试。
So let's try.
我们继续按Enter键，知道它已经熄灭了。
Let's go ahead and press enter and know that that's gone out.
这一次它没有出现在屏幕上。
It doesn't come up on the screen this time.
如果我们看这里，我们有一个叫做今天的文件。
And if we look in here we've got a file called today that takes t.
如果我们点击它，我们现在看到的是周一。
And if we click it we've now got Monday.
这不是很棒吗。
Isn't that awesome.
我觉得这太棒了。
I think that's fantastic.
现在作为附注，实际上我将重定向放在哪里并不重要。
Now as a side note it doesn't actually matter where I put the redirection.
好的。
OK.
这样我就可以在这里结束重定向了。
So I could have the redirection at the end here.
我可以在这里重定向，但它仍然会工作得一模一样。
I could have the redirection over here and it would still work exactly the same.
好的。
OK.
这绝对行得通。
That that works absolutely fine.
我甚至可以把它放在不同的选项之间，这样我就可以把它放在这里。
I could even actually put it in between the different options so I could put it here.
我也会一如既往地工作。
And I will also work exactly the same.
好的。
OK.
我们今天还会看到XTi博士周一在里面。
We're still getting today Dr. XTi with Monday inside.
所以这只是一件需要牢记在心的事情。
So that's just something to bear in mind.
好的，不要害怕打错东西。
OK don't be scared about typing stuff wrong.
所有这些都是有效的方法，但有些只是比其他的可读性强得多。
All of these are valid ways to do it but some are just a lot more readable than others.
好的，但是假设我们不是重定向，而是希望发送Cut命令的标准输出
OK but let's say that instead of redirecting we wanted to send the standard output of the cut command
对于另一个命令，我们将如何做到这一点，而不是将其保存到文件中，我们将如何
to yet another command how would we do that how would instead of saving it into a file how would we
将数据从该命令发送到另一个命令。
send the data from the command into yet another command.
嗯，这很简单。
Well it's simple.
你只要往管子里加水就行了。
You just add into the pipe.
好的，所以你只要说，好的，让我把它剪掉。
OK so you just say OK let me cut that.
但是不，对不起，让我把它放到管子下面，然后我们分开指挥。
But no sorry let me just put under the pipe and then let's separate command.
我有一些选项，然后我有一些命令行参数，这就是它的工作方式。
I've got some options and then I've got some command line arguments and that's how that would work.
好的。
OK.
这个新命令可以接受它自己的选项，它自己的命令行参数，并且它还可以读取
That this new command could take its own options its own command line arguments and it could also read
来自命令行的标准输入，这样您就可以看到它是如何工作的。
standard input from the command line so you can see how this works.
我们花了一天的时间，将输出通过管道传输到标准输入，即给定的CUT命令的CUT命令
We take taken the day come and piping the output into standard input the cut command given the cut command
它自己的选择。
its own options.
然后，我们将输出通过管道传输到另一个命令，该命令有自己的选项和自己的命令
Then we're piping the output into another command given that command its own options and its own command
争论等等等等。
arguments and so on and so on and so on.
好的，你可以继续把这些东西放在一起，做你想做的，然后给他们选择
OK you can just keep on going piping these things together doing what you want and giving them options
随便你。
as you wish.
这就是整个Linux终端的动力所在。
So this is what gives the the whole Linux terminal its power.
好的。
OK.
到目前为止，我们一直在做一些很酷但不一定真的有用的事情，但是当你可以
Up until now we've been doing things that are cool but not really necessarily useful but when you can
将真正强大的命令组合在一起，让它们完全按照您想要的方式运行
combine together really powerful commands and have them operating exactly exactly the way that you want
在他们之间和你的计算机上传递数据，这真的很令人惊叹。
to impart the data between them and all over your computer it really gets amazing.
所以你可以看到这些管道可以不停地延伸，你可以看到如何建造一条强大的管道
So you can see that this pipings can go on and on and you can see how to build a powerful pipeline this
道路。
way.
实际上非常简单，您只需将不同的命令组合在一起即可。
It's actually really straightforward you just pipe together different commands.
这不是很棒吗。
Isn't that awesome.
所以让我问你一个问题。
So let me ask you a question.
如果我们希望将整个日期保存在一个文件中，然后将其传递到管道中，该怎么办？
What if we wanted to actually keep the whole date in a file and then pass it into a pipe.
我们不能在这里简单地使用重定向，因为我们已经传递了
Well we can't simply use a redirection at the end here because we're already passing the the sum of
将它们的DATE命令部分转换为命令。
their part of the date command into the command.
正确的。
Right.
所以我们不能真的将其保存在文件中，因为我们已经在沿着管道传递它了。
So we can't really save it in a file because we're already passing it on down the pipeline.
如果我们试着这样做，如果我们试着这样做，你知道，如果我们试着只通过管道输出，那么就去掉末尾
And if we tried to do it if we tried to you know get rid of the end if we tried to just pipe the output
进入Dotti XTi的日子里，如果我们这样做，那么我们就会删除这里的所有东西。
into day Dotti XTi if we do that then we just delete everything we've got in here.
这样我们就可以看到效果了。
So we can see the effect.
如果我试一下，我们会发现我们得到的只是Date dot t s t。
If I try this we'll see the all we get is just date dot t s t.
好的，所有的数据都保存在今天的胶带里。
OK the whole data is saved in today duct tape.
但这样就没有什么可以传递给指挥部了。
But then there's nothing to pass on into the command.
好的。
OK.
这是因为改道前处理的管道在淋浴的地方。
This is because redirections a processed before pipes where in the shower.
因此，您找到重定向，并在它看到管道之前执行此操作。
So you find the redirection and do that before it ever sees the pipe.
好的。
OK.
这基本上切断了我们的管道。
And this basically breaks our pipeline.
所以数据不可能同时到达两个地方。
So the data can't really go two places at once.
很好，我们将使用一个叫做T命令的命令，它是一种高级的
It well to make this work we're going to use a command called the T command and it's these kind of advanced
我们将在下一个视频中向您展示的内容。
stuff that we're going to be showing you in the next video.